

KHALED BEN HASSEN

FULL-STACK SOFTWARE ENGINEER

CONTACT



(+216) 22 84 47 72



khaled.benhassen@polytechnicien.tn



linkedin.com/in/khaled-bhassan



github.com/Klodovsky (Personal)



github.com/KhaledSMIT (Work)



Sousse, Tunisia

PORTFOLIO



khaledbenhassen.netlify.app

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

Programming languages:

- PHP
- Python
- Coldfusion
- Scala

Web development:

- JavaScript
- TypeScript
- Node.js
- · Bootstrap/Tailwind
- HTML/CSS
- Webpack

Framework:

- Laravel
- Vue.js
- Nuxt.js
- Django

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Qualified, forward-Hooking Software Engineer with over 3 years background in creating and executing innovative software solutions to enhance business productivity. Highly experienced in all aspects of the software development life cycle from concept through to development and delivery.

Confident communicator, strategic thinker, and Well-versed in technology and writing code to develop and design software that is customized to meet a company's organizational needs, highlight their core competencies, and further their success.

EXPERIENCE

FULL-STACK SOFTWARE ENGINEER Smart Management IT Solutions | Doha, Qatar

Apr 2021 - Present

- Developing, designing, and delivering new ERP systems and upgrading existing ones for use by business clients.
- Collaborating with different IT teams (Developers, Designers, Devops) to establish and test interfaces.
- Working with internal and external business partners to streamline business processes, improve operational efficiencies, identify and fix current issues.
- Creating and maintaining ERP designs and coding standards as well as providing custom coding.
- Reduced loading time by centralizing all the states of various UI controls in order to handle data flow across the application.

Tech stack: Laravel, Vue.js, Vuex, SQL, Git, Scrum, Jira.

FULL-STACK JS DEVELOPER Sourceamax | Grenoble office, France

May 2020 - Jan 2021

- Worked alongside project manager to process the migration of an online survey tool made available to the company's customers in SaaS mode.
- Developed a graphical redesign using Vue.js and it's ecosystem with a focus on obtaining user-friendly interfaces.
- Updated analysis modules and the restitution of data in real time.
- Tested and integrated multiple modern Business Intelligence technologies.

Databases:

- MySQL / PostgreSQL (SQL)
- MongoDB / Redis (NoSQL)

Containerization:

Docker

Software architecture and project management :

• MVC, MTV, MVVM, UML, Scrum.

SOFT SKILLS

- Problem-Solving
- · Creativity and imagination
- Strong Communication
- Teamwork
- Flexibility
- · Friendliness and manners

LANGUAGES

INTERESTS

- Music composition
- · Cyber security
- Blockchain

REFERENCE

RAMZI MAHMOUDI Phd, head of IT departement Ramzi.mahmoudi@esiee.fr

ROBIN SEVE

Manager, Source@max Robin.seve@sourceamax.com

AMIR BOUKER

Tech Lead, Paramount Soft amir@paramountsoft.net

 Collected and filtered data from internal IT systems and external sources, prepared it for analysis, and customized queries against the data in order to create data visualizations.

Tech stack: ColdFusion, Python, Vue.js, Vuetify.js, Microsoft SQL

Server, Power BI, Qlik Sense, Zoho Analytics, Linux, Git.

FULL-STACK JS DEVELOPER MEDCOM PROD | Sousse, Tunisia

Aug 2019 - Apr 2020

- Contributed to multiple software projects simultaneously and participated in the whole software development process from software design to implementation and delivery.
- Developed a cyber breach response plan.
- Encountered end users to study business methods, realize needs, and recommending technical answers.
- Studied and distributed help documents related to customization, designs, and reports.

Tech stack: Laravel, MariaDB, Sass, Git.

PHP DEVELOPER

Advanced Technologies Software (ATS) | Ariana, Tunisia

Mar 2019 - Aug 2019

- Designed and developed a crowdfunding web application.
- Integrated Razor-pay payment gateway.
- Developed micro-services and Web Services (incl.REST/SOAP/XML).
- Created visual representation of support received, the classification of initiatives and campaign monitoring.
- Ran monthly unit tests to determine software effectiveness and mend broken links or glitches in the system.

Tech stack: Code-igniter 3, MySQL, Bootstrap ,Razor-pay.

EDUCATION

POLYTECHNIQUE SCHOOL OF SOUSSE | SOUSSE, TUNISIA Software Engineer Diploma

2017 - 2020

POLYTECHNIQUE SCHOOL OF SOUSSE | SOUSSE, TUNISIA INTEGRATED PREPARATORY CYCLE

2015 - 2017

ABOU KACEM CHEBBI HIGH SCHOOL | MAHDIA, TUNISIA High School Diploma, Computer Science

2009 - 2013

EXTRACURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

AIESEC | SOUSSE, TUNISIA

• Interviewed and trained the new members along with the local training team.

Google Club Polytechnique School of Sousse | SOUSSE, TUNISIA

- Organized and participated in regional and national coding contests.
- Taught new joiners web development and music composition.

Tunisian Association for the Future of Science and Technology (ATAST)

• Been affiliated with a young scientists association applying their imagination and their creativity to technology innovations.